let htmlquestions = {
    time : 23 , //in minutes
    questions: [{
        question: "1. HTML stands for?",
        option1: "Hypertext Markup Language",
        option2: "Hyper Makeup Language",
        option3: "Web development",
        option4: "Hamara Mark Language",
        correctresponse: "Hypertext Markup Language",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "2. Which tag is used to define a paragraph in HTML?",
        option1: "<h1>",
        option2: "<p>",
        option3: "<br>",
        option4: "<b>",
        correctresponse: "<p>",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "3. What is the correct syntax for creating a hyperlink in HTML?",
        option1: "<a href='url'>link text</a>",
        option2: "<link url=''>link text</link>",
        option3: "http://www.example.com",
        option4: "<url>link text</url>",
        correctresponse: "<a href='url'>link text</a>",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "4. Which tag is used to create an unordered list in HTML?",
        option1: "<ol>",
        option2: "<ul>",
        option3: "<li>",
        option4: "<dl>",
        correctresponse: "<ul>",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "5. What is the purpose of the <img> tag in HTML?",
        option1: "To insert an image",
        option2: "To create a table",
        option3: "To define a form",
        option4: "To add a background color",
        correctresponse: "To insert an image",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "6. Which attribute is used to specify the source of an image in the <img> tag?",
        option1: "src",
        option2: "href",
        option3: "alt",
        option4: "title",
        correctresponse: "src",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "7. What is the purpose of the <br> tag in HTML?",
        option1: "To create a new line",
        option2: "To create a heading",
        option3: "To create a table row",
        option4: "To create a list item",
        correctresponse: "To create a new line",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "8. Which tag is used to define a table in HTML?",
        option1: "<table>",
        option2: "<tr>",
        option3: "<td>",
        option4: "<th>",
        correctresponse: "<table>",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "9. Which tag is used to define a table row in HTML?",
        option1: "<table>",
        option2: "<tr>",
        option3: "<td>",
        option4: "<th>",
        correctresponse: "<tr>",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "10. Which tag is used to define a table cell in HTML?",
        option1: "<table>",
        option2: "<tr>",
        option3: "<td>",
        option4: "<th>",
        correctresponse: "<td>",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "11. Which tag is used to define a table header cell in HTML?",
        option1: "<table>",
        option2: "<tr>",
        option3: "<td>",
        option4: "<th>",
        correctresponse: "<th>",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "12. What is the purpose of the <div> tag in HTML?",
        option1: "To define a division or section of a document",
        option2: "To create a hyperlink",
        option3: "To insert an image",
        option4: "To create a list",
        correctresponse: "To define a division or section of a document",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "13. What is the purpose of the <span> tag in HTML?",
        option1: "To group inline elements",
        option2: "To create a heading",
        option3: "To create a table",
        option4: "To create a list",
        correctresponse: "To group inline elements",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "14. Which attribute is used to specify the style of an HTML element?",
        option1: "class",
        option2: "id",
        option3: "style",
        option4: "href",
        correctresponse: "style",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "15. What is the purpose of the <form> tag in HTML?",
        option1: "To create an HTML form for user input",
        option2: "To create a table",
        option3: "To insert an image",
        option4: "To create a list",
        correctresponse: "To create an HTML form for user input",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "16. Which input type is used to create a text field in HTML?",
        option1: "text",
        option2: "submit",
        option3: "radio",
        option4: "checkbox",
        correctresponse: "text",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "17. Which input type is used to create a submit button in HTML?",
        option1: "text",
        option2: "submit",
        option3: "radio",
        option4: "checkbox",
        correctresponse: "submit",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "18. Which input type is used to create a checkbox in HTML?",
        option1: "text",
        option2: "submit",
        option3: "radio",
        option4: "checkbox",
        correctresponse: "checkbox",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "19. Which input type is used to create a radio button in HTML?",
        option1: "text",
        option2: "submit",
        option3: "radio",
        option4: "checkbox",
        correctresponse: "radio",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "20. What is the purpose of the <head> section in HTML?",
        option1: "To contain meta-information about the HTML document",
        option2: "To contain the main content of the HTML document",
        option3: "To contain the styles for the HTML document",
        option4: "To contain the scripts for the HTML document",
        correctresponse: "To contain meta-information about the HTML document",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "21. What is the purpose of the <title> tag in HTML?",
        option1: "To define the title that appears in the browser tab or window",
        option2: "To define a heading for the document",
        option3: "To define the author of the document",
        option4: "To define the keywords for the document",
        correctresponse: "To define the title that appears in the browser tab or window",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "22. What is the purpose of the <meta> tag in HTML?",
        option1: "To provide meta-information about the HTML document",
        option2: "To create a hyperlink",
        option3: "To insert an image",
        option4: "To create a list",
        correctresponse: "To provide meta-information about the HTML document",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "23. What is the purpose of the <style> tag in HTML?",
        option1: "To define internal style rules for the HTML document",
        option2: "To link to an external stylesheet",
        option3: "To define the title of the document",
        option4: "To define the author of the document",
        correctresponse: "To define internal style rules for the HTML document",
        time: 1
      },
]
}

export default htmlquestions